You have reached the final module.
Over the last six modules, we have built a massive enterprise foundation.
Now it's time to prepare for the certification.
The Google Cloud Professional DevOps Engineer exam is unique
because it does not just test if you know the tools,
it tests if you can apply SRE principles to organizational challenges.
Let's understand the specific question formats you will encounter and the
strategies you need to navigate them under the pressure.
Most of the questions are multiple choice,
but they are really simply definitions.
For example, instead of asking what is shared VPC in the exam,
you will be asked,
your security team requires central control over networking while
giving developers autonomy over their compute resources.
Which networking model should you use? Now in this
architecture kind of a question, you have to look for the constraint.
In this example,
the central control with autonomy is the hallmark of the shared VPC.
Another one is a scenario‑based reasoning.
You will be presented with a company's current state,
with generally a messy state and a desired future state.
In these kinds of questions,
many times you can solve this by using strategic elimination.
You can often find the right answer by spotting the distractors.
Another strategy that can be applied is the flag and move strategy,
that is for your time management.
You have 120 minutes for roughly 50‑60 questions.
Do not let a three‑paragraph scenario derail your rhythm.
If you don't know the answer in 60 seconds, flag it and move on.
Once you've finished with all the questions, you can review it and work on it.